Next up
we have our video presentation I believe.
So you'll just give us a few seconds
to queue that up.
We do have Yolanda De Gregorio with us,
but she is on a train,
so we have a video performance here
or presentation,
I should say.
Hello.
Well, first,
thank you very much for the organization
to give me the opportunity
to give my talk.
And also thank you
to all of you for being here with us.
Coding, the wild data, poetics,
artificial intelligence
and more than human futures
in mechanical tree house.
Mechanical tree
House is a work of avant garde
literature created collaboratively
by A Link to Craft and Jason Nelson,
representing a milestone in the
convergence of artificial intelligence
and digital narrative.
The authors define
this piece as an ultra large
digital narrative.
Agenda, coined
by Nelson to describe multimodal poems
that construct moving
visual and auditory
walls of almost unlimited scope.
Although I prefer to call it
an animated digital tapestry,
unlike a standard detailed image,
this works written massive dimensions
of over
30,000 pixels in white and file sizes
between 50 and 100MB, requiring
the assembly of hundreds of AI generated
frames.
This scale allows the work to function
as an animated data tapestry,
just as the ancient ghoul or sink
tapestries told stories on the wolves.
This one is
woven from pixels
and movement, giving it a life of its own
that resent the static nature
of traditional media.
The work integrates test
image and constantly evolving
visual grammar to explore a hybrid
narrative ecosystem where nature,
technology and post-human world converge.
In this subject, that logical
and human converge
into a single narrative body, suggesting
that analogies can act as agents
within our social sphere.
The piece function as a living organisms,
where the internal and simultaneous
McEnany of cogs and pipes integrates
with faces and wind figures.
Artificial intelligence
is the central creative tool
used specifically
through the technique of out
painting, with models such as Dale.
This process allows allows the artist
to start with a central visual idea
and spend it in multiple directions.
Enable the code to anticipate
and generate surrounding landscapes
based on what is immediately
connected to it.
In this co-creation process, the
AI does not replace the artist, but serves
as a same intelligent collaborator.
Jason Nelson
and A Link to Craft describe this work
as an interactive conversation
in which the artist manipulates
the algorithms, bias,
and tendencies,
even using its error or hallucinations
as source of poetic inspiration
in a method they terms.
The term frank coding for the authors.
The aim is not for AI to write the poetry,
but for it to help make possible
what was previously technically
technically almost impossible,
such as the creation of highly
complex visual structures.
The poignant falls in a
vertical landscape of three cities
inspired by Alinta.
Krauss, author
ethnographic accounts of her childhood
in the subtropical forests of Australia.
The narrative directly addresses
the climate crisis, recounting
how generations living in a warming world
cause sea levels to rise.
That influence floods
into the new seasons.
Against this backdrop of global
change, Mechanical Treehouse
propose ecological and swift
and sustainable architectures
where Herrmann infrastructure
does not eliminate the forests
but integrates with it.
Building houses in the sky.
Far from dry land,
the visual narrative is organized
into seven written sections,
set with white frames
that guide the reader
through this hopeful future.
The work is in death,
Sam biotic relationship
and the concept of the more than human,
a philosophy
that seeks to defend the human subject
in favor to other creatures, critters,
and materials
that have historically been marginalized.
In this image, future
electricity flows
through the good in a symbiotic embrace
that supplies energy and nutrients
to both the build and the cultivated.
Furthermore, green technology
takes the form of a distributed
AI created by the trees on leaves,
which continuously
adjust the elevation of the houses
using pulleys and lifting mechanisms.
As the seasonal water level rises,
this vision aligns with craft's research
into sensory affordances, where
artistic design six
not only human approval,
but also takes into account the needs
and perception of other species.
In this hybrid ecosystem,
the energy for intensive task
came from gravity
and coordinated movement.
Humans leap from balconies to to power
turbines, creating a music of their stand
and descent
that resonates throughout the forest
canopy.
Animals have also evolved.
Birds have reverted to their forms,
functioning as a modern dinosaurs
that causes with humans
not as pest as a pets,
but as patterns and companions
who attend seeds and fruit for shelter
and love.
This thought
poetic approach reflects clouds commitment
to animal warfare and interspecies
empathy.
Empathy. Empathy. Themes.
She also explored in the works
such as The Motherhood of Meat,
in which she uses AI
to translate bad vocalization into poems
for theoretical perspective.
Mechanical tree house forms
part of an eco critical tradition
that utilizes interactive media
to propose ethical solutions
for beetle ecosystems.
The work can be understood as a response
to the analysis of extinction
and climate change,
as these are processes of such bars
and complex scale.
Krauss argues
that they can only be narrated
through fragmentation
and algorithmic combinatorics.
The creation of of such detailed words
function as an act of ecological mourning,
a ritual practice to acknowledge
what is being lost, and to just analogy
as a speculative conduit
for connecting with non-human.
The significance of this work stands
to a spin off.
Projects.
Projects such as branching narrative
and interactive version
commissioned by Golden Cows Airport.
In the second part, Krauss apply video
game design processes to enable families
and children to interact with the world
of three cities by releasing birth
or operating lives, thereby
reinforcing the idea that data literature
is an educational tool
for imagining sustainable futures.
Finally, Creighton Nelson demonstrates
that digital literature
is not merely a technological medium,
but an inseparable whole
in which machine and human thought
convert to a stay with the problem
and find hope in a
war on the brink of collapse.
In conclusion.
Mechanical Treehouse
is not just a visual poem,
it is an essay on resilience
and interspecies collaboration.
Digital age.
By using AI as a collaborator
and as that descent the human,
the working by the user to participate
in the transformation
of our relationship with nature,
it demonstrates that contemporary epoch
has the unique capacity
to address, to address
the most pressing challenges
of the Anthropocene.
Turning code and pixels into tools for
imagining a more than human and deeply
sustainable future.
Thank you very much.